William Henry Allison Diaries
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
William Henry Allison Diaries 1868-1940
MSS91546
Allison, William Henry, 1870-1941
58 items 15 containers 4.5 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Historian and clergyman. Diaries kept by Allison recording his daily activities as a historian, clergyman, and consultant to the Library of Congress in church history. Includes a diary, 1868-1869, kept by his grandmother, Mary Ireland Allison, and an index to the volumes.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Allison, Mary Ireland, -1870. Mary Ireland Allison diary. 1868-1869.; Allison, William Henry, 1870-1941.
Organizations
Bryn Mawr College--Faculty.; Colgate University--Faculty.; Library of Congress.; Pacific Theological Seminary (Berkeley, Calif.)--Faculty.; Penacook Baptist Church (Concord, N.H.)
Subjects
Baptists--Clergy.; Baptists--New Hampshire--Concord.; Church history.
Occupations
Clergy.; Historians.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The diaries of William Henry Allison, historian and clergyman, were given to the Library of Congress by his wife, Emily Mills Allison, in 1941.
Access and Restrictions
The diaries of William Henry Allison are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of William Henry Allison (1870-1941) span the years 1868-1940 and consist entirely of diaries and an index to these volumes. A diary kept by Allison’s grandmother, Mary Ireland Allison, covers the period 1868-1869. Allison's diaries chronicle his daily activities as a historian at Pacific Theological Seminary, Bryn Mawr College, Colgate University, and other universities, as a clergyman at Penacook Baptist Church, Concord, New Hampshire, 1899-1902, and as a consultant in church history to the Library of Congress, 1930-1941.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged chronologically.
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm82091546
Container List
- Diaries (Box 1-15)
  - Allison, Mary Ireland, 1868-1869 (Box 1)
  - Allison, William Henry (Box 1)
    - Indexes, (2 vols.) (Box 1)
    - 1886-1889, (4 vols.) (Box 2)
    - 1890-1893, (4 vols.) (Box 3)
    - 1894-1897, (4 vols.) (Box 4)
    - 1898-1901, (4 vols.) (Box 5)
    - 1902-1905, (4 vols.) (Box 6)
    - 1906-1909, (4 vols.) (Box 7)
    - 1910-1913, (4 vols.) (Box 8)
    - 1914-1917, (4 vols.) (Box 9)
    - 1918-1921, (4 vols.) (Box 10)
    - 1922-1925, (4 vols.) (Box 11)
    - 1926-1929, (4 vols.) (Box 12)
    - 1930-1933, (4 vols.) (Box 13)
    - 1934-1937, (4 vols.) (Box 14)
    - 1938-1940, (3 vols.) (Box 15)